Mahmoud Madkour

Software Developer

- +201097894855
- mahhmoudmadkour@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-
- madkour-24-6-20 github.com/Mahmod-Madkour
- **&** Giza, Egypt

Summary

Graduate with a degree in Computer Science from Thebes Academy 2022. Has a problem-solving and data structures skill. Has a Professional and Advanced certificate from Udacity in data analysis. Experience in data analysis and visualization specific to Python. Currently learning about backend development. Excited to learn new techniques and is proficient in his work.

Work Experience

Freelance

Up Work & khamsat Jan 2022 - present

- Worked with more than 5 clients.
- Managed a project that met all client requirements and modifications and was delivered on time.

Trainee

QNB AlAhli Bank Cairo, Egypt Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

- Worked in the leasing department.
- Creating more than 10 contracts for customers, following up on their papers, including checks and insurance, and examining more than 50% of customer contracts to follow up on the payment of their installments.

Education

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science Thebes Academy Sep 2018 – Jun 2022

Qualifications

Data Analysis Professional by Udacity
Advanced Data Analysis by Udacity

<u>certificate link</u>
<u>certificate link</u>

Skills

Personal Skills

- Communication
- Organization
- Work Under Pressure
- Problem-Solving
- Self-Learning
- Research

Professional Skills

- C++, C#, PhP, Python
- Data StructureGit & GitHub
- Data Analysis
- OOP
- Statistics
- SQL
- Data Visualization

Projects

ASL Sign Language App (Graduation Project)

It is a Mobile App whose idea is to help the deaf, by translating signs using the camera into words so that we can understand them, and vice versa, translating words into signs so that they can understand us. My role was to create and train the translation model using Machin Learning.

Techniques: Flutter, Python, TensorFlow, Firebase, Figma, System Design, Agile.

We Rate Dogs

More than 5,000 tweets were collected in the dataset containing dog ratings from the @WeRateDogs Twitter account to Assessing and Cleaning the dataset. Based on the ratings, we concluded that ratings increase over time and the most and least common stages in dogs and others concluded.

Techniques: Python, NumPy, Pandas, Data Wrangling, Visualization, Matplotlib, Seaborn.

Bike Share

This is a project to compare the system usage between three large cities in the US (Chicago - New Yor - Washington) to analyze and find out popular times of travel, popular stations and trip, and trip duration. **Techniques:** Python, Data Structure, OOP.

Achievement

ACPC (AFRICA & ARAB Collegiate Programming Championship)

I won a fourth place in the 2020 Thebes Higher Institute Collegiate Programming Contest.

Finished Military Service

Language

Arabic Native
English Intermediate